I won't let your deaths be meaningless
even if I'm the last one standing
In both hands, Gloria
What sings is Sieg
On my back, Flügel der Freiheit
Clenched determination to my left chest
What slashes across is Linie der Torheit
Soaring across the azure skies
Flügel der Freiheit
"What Needs to be Done Now"
"Eve of the Counterattack, Part 3"
When did you last replace your shaft?
Six days ago, after the mop-up operation.
Records confirm.
All right. You're next.
Christa Lenz of Squad 42!
Equipment check.
So killing Titans can actually
get you in trouble, huh?
Yeah, it's crazy, but they were
valuable test subjects.
Even so, why are they searching for
the culprits among us cadets?
Yeah, we're worn out enough as it is,
cleaning up the battlefield all this time...
Whoever it was really hates Titans.
Mm...
But they pretty much
helped the Titans, if anything.
Maybe it helped quench their
thirst for revenge,
but it was also a
big setback for humanity.
I'm not too bright,
so I think I can relate.
Before I actually saw a Titan,
I seriously planned on joining the Scouts.
Now I never want
to see another one again.
But today's the day we
hafta pick a regiment to join...
Is Jean seriously going to...?
Everyone's having regrets...
They never would've
chosen to be soldiers
if they knew this
hell awaited them...
Now that they're utterly drained,
that's the only thing
they can think about...
Marco...
I don't know which
bones are yours anymore...
If I hadn't become a soldier,
I never would've had
to worry about who's next...
Are we just going to throw away
all the advances in fighting techniques
that cost us tens of thousands
of lives so we can be Titan fodder?!
I know I have to fight.
But not everyone can
be a suicidal maniac like you...
I don't mean any offense by this,
but I think the fact you aren't strong
really lets you understand how the weak feel.
And your skill at recognizing
a situation as it unfolds
gives you a clear grasp of what
needs to be done now, you know?
What needs to be done now...
Hey, guys.
Have you decided which
regiment you're going to join?
I have.
I'm...
...going to join the Scouts!
Damn...
Hey, Annie. What do you think?
Jean says he's gonna join the Scouts.
Huh? Jean is?
Don't really care.
Yeah, you're joining the Military Police.
Maybe I should too after all?
Tell me, if someone
told you to die, would you?
What? No.
Then do what matters most to you.
What about you, Armin?
Huh? I...
I think I might, if the situation called
for it and I understood the reason why.
Not that I'd want to.
I see. So you've decided.
Mm.
Although it was always my plan anyway.
Oh, man. Not you too, Armin?
For as weak as you are, you've got guts.
Th-Thanks.
You know, you're actually pretty nice, Annie.
Huh?
I mean, you seem apprehensive
about us joining the Scouts,
plus I assume you have a reason
for joining the Military Police, right?
Not really.
I just want to stay alive.
In the end, it seems they never found
whoever used the ODM gear
without permission.
--Who could it have been?
--Beats me.
Right now, I'm more worried about
the upcoming rookie solicitation.
How many rookies will be willing
to join us just for the hell of it?
Hey, Eren.
Is there anyone in your
class who's thinking of joining us?
There are.
Well, there were.
I'm not sure about now.
Assemble!
Make ready at once!
We're going on patrol!
Yes, Sir!
Good morning, Captain Levi!
Listen, Eren. Don't fall
more than two lengths behind.
You're only allowed to wander
around because I'm watching you.
Don't forget that.
Yes, Sir!
Let's go!
Jean!
Are you really joining the Scouts?
Yeah.
Why the sudden change of heart?
I mean... aren't you afraid?
Huh? Of course
I don't like the lousy Scouts.
Huh? Then, why are you...?
It's not 'cause I'm not scared
of the Titans or anything like that.
Nor am I gonna say that capable
people should join the Scouts.
I'm not like that suicidal maniac.
Eren, huh?
He's already been a Scout for a while now.
Cadets!
Fall in!
Face the platform!
No one's persuaded
me into risking my life, either.
This is one time where
the decision has to be all mine.
I am Commander Erwin Smith
of the Scout Regiment.
Today, you choose a regiment to join.
To put it bluntly, this is my
invitation for you to join the Scouts.
I am sure that,
after this recent Titan attack,
you've already come
to know their horror,
as well as the limits of your own abilities.
However!
Through this battle,
humanity has gained an unprecedented
advancement toward victory.
I'm referring to Eren Jaeger.
He has proven,
by risking life and limb,
that he is unquestionably on our side.
What's more, he has helped
us not only foil the Titans' invasion,
but given us a way to learn
the truth behind the Titans as well!
We have reason to believe that the
basement of his home in Shiganshina
houses a secret of the
Titans that not even he is aware of.
If we can just reach this basement,
we may be able to obtain information
that will help us break free
from the Titans' century-long tyranny.
Basement?
Things have already progressed this far?
If we can figure out what the Titans are,
we can turn the tables on them!
However badly he wants new recruits,
going public with this is too much...
Or is this part of some sort of plan?
Just what is the commander looking for?!
We will head for the basement
in Shiganshina District.
However, doing so will require
taking back Wall Maria.
In other words, our goal is the
same as it's always been...
...but now that Trost's gate is unusable,
we've no choice but to depart from
Calaneth District, further to the east.
The entire battalion route we spent
four years establishing is now useless.
During those four years,
over 60% of the Scouts died.
60% in four years.
Truly unbelievable numbers.
In one month there will
be an outside scouting mission.
New recruits from
your class will take part in it,
of which I estimate 30% will die.
And in four years, most will be dead.
However, whoever prevails
will have become a highly skilled
soldier who can survive anything.
Knowing this dismal state of affairs,
whoever still wishes to put
their life on the line, remain here.
Ask yourself...
...if you can give your heart for
the sake of humankind!
That is all.
Those who wish to join
other regiments may leave.
Sir!
Don't you think that was overly intimidating?!
No one's going to stay behind now!
Damn...
Please... I've already decided!
Don't make me hate
myself any more than this...!
If I don't walk away now,
I'll have to go through that again!
I originally left my village to
join the Military Police...
Mom will be so happy...
And if I join the Military Police,
everyone will finally respect me too...
But now we know it...
Now we've seen it...
How the Titans...
...eat people!
If you cadets were
told to die, could you?
We don't wish to die, Sir!
I see. You each have
an outstanding look about you.
All of you here are hereby accepted
as new members of the Scout Regiment!
This is a genuine salute!
Give your hearts!
Yes, Sir!
Everyone...
Joining the Scouts... Man, this sucks...
I'm scared! I wanna go home!
I don't care anymore...
If you're gonna cry, then don't stay.
You've done well to endure your fear.
You're all brave soldiers.
I respect you from the bottom of my heart.
Salute!
I'm Section Commander Ness.
And this is my horse, Charrette.
Charrette likes to pull hair,
so watch out if you don't wanna go bald.
It's nice to meet you.
You idiot! Stop that, Charrette!
Someone do something! Hey!
Our training began the next day.
However, it was focused
less on actual combat
and more on having Commander Erwin's
long-range scouting formation
drummed into our heads.
Oddly enough, although it
was a precise, calculated formation,
Eren Jaeger's position
was nowhere to be found.
You rookies will be here,
between the wagon defense
squad and the scout support squad.
Here, you will run alongside
spare horses and relay signals.
Our special operations
squad will be positioned here,
on standby in the rear of the center rank.
That's pretty far back.
This is the safest position in the formation.
Not even the supply
wagons get this level of treatment.
Our goal this time is simply
to leave and come back, though.
This expedition is meant to
be short, as it's also a test run
to see if we can get you all
the way to Shiganshina or not.
Umm...
I still don't really know what
to do with this ability of mine...
Do you understand what the
commander asked you back then?
Huh?
What do you think the enemy is?
Do any of you know what he meant?
Nope.
I'd be lying if I said I understood it all.
--But I--
--It's possible...
...there's another goal to this operation.
But the commander decided it doesn't
need to be explained to the soldiers.
In which case, leaving and
coming back is all we should focus on.
Have faith in the commander.
Yes, Sir.
That's all for today's training.
Prepare to head back.
Oh, it's them!
Mr. Oruo!
May I go talk with
my classmates for a minute?!
Tch. Go on.
Hey! Mikasa! Armin!
Eren!
It feels like it's been forever!
Eren...
Have they mistreated you in any way?!
Like studying and
examining every bit of you
or putting you through mental anguish?!
N-No, not at all...
That pipsqueak went way too far.
Someday I will make him pay.
Are you talking about Captain Levi?
Hey, Eren!
Long time, no see!
Oh!
You're all here?!
But...
If you're here... does that
mean you joined the Scouts?
Why else would we be here?
Then just Jean, Annie,
and Marco joined the Military Police?
Wait, you too?!
Marco's dead.
Huh?
What did you just say?
Did you say Marco's dead?
Apparently not everyone can
die in a dramatic way.
I don't even know how he went out.
He died all alone,
without anyone knowing or seeing.
Marco did...?
Hey! Gather 'round, rookies!
Your uniforms are here!
Are you guys really...?
Yes. We're taking part
in the upcoming operation too.
Hey, Eren.
I heard you tried to kill
Mikasa when you turned into a Titan.
What's all that about?
It's not like that.
He was swatting at a fly.
I'm not asking you.
Actually, Mikasa.
That cut on your cheek looks pretty deep.
When did you get it?
Apparently it's true. I tried to
kill Mikasa when I was in Titan form.
Apparently? Meaning you don't remember?
So, basically, you never knew
about this Titan ability of yours until now
and you don't have full control over it?
Yeah. That's right.
Hear that, guys? Sounds like
this is the current situation.
Our lives and the lives of all
humankind rest on his shoulders.
We'll probably end up just like
Marco too: dead before Eren knows it.
Jean. What's the point in
chastising Eren now?
Y'know, Mikasa...
Not everyone is willing to
needlessly die for Eren like you.
We should know what
we're laying down our lives for.
Otherwise we'll end up
hesitating when the time comes.
We're asking Eren for a guarantee.
Show us what you're worth...
...so we can see if our
lives are worth as much.
So, Eren!
We're really counting on you, you hear?!
Y-Yeah...
Commander. It's almost time.
We've lured the nearby Titans away!
Thirty seconds to gate opening!
It's the Scouts!
The marks on their backs
are called the Wings of Freedom!
So cool!
This is it!
Humanity is now about
to take another step forward!
Show us what you're made of!
Open the gate!
Forward!
Now commencing the
57th Exterior Scouting Mission!
Move out!
If, by chance, I'm not me
then who's to say that you're you?
Can you pick up the pieces of your heart
that fell apart like a broken sand castle?
The voice of someone calling out
changed into ringing in my ears
It's as if time has stopped
Now wake up
I made my way out of the deep darkness
I fled like a swift wind
We used to be like living corpses,
but now we head beyond the walls
Let's meet again
in a place not on any map
The Scout Regiment takes up
its long-range scouting formation
and makes progress beyond the wall.
Suddenly, they encounter
a mysterious, intelligent Titan.
"Female Titan"
"The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 1"